It makes me want to do things like uh
name my user that string, you know,
name, you know, put my email like as
like a plus alias like reszo plus that
big long string at wehacker1.com. Like
just basically just get that string
anywhere I can. [music]
Best part of backing when you can just,
you know, critical think, right?
[laughter]
>> Yeah, dude.
>> Hey, what's up, guys? I just had a quick
little uh snippet here for you from the
Adobe team for CTB listeners. They're
doing an AI campaign and if you use code
CTB04126,
you get a 10% bonus on your bounty for
any AI vulnerability which is mapped to
the OASP LLM top 10. So just do that
before April 1st of this year. And uh
it's true for the products that are
Adobe Acrobat Web AI assistant, PDF
spaces, content creation and
presentation features using Express and
then their Adobe Express AI assistant.
So make sure you check that out and get
a 10% bonus on your bounty.
All right, dude. What's up? How have you
been?
>> I've been good, mate. It's been a while.
How about yourself? What's been going
on? Many bugs, lots of research. What's
been happening?
>> Oh, man. I feel like well 2025 was a
tough year in general for our family,
but this month we've also had some tough
stuff going on. Um, hacking wise though,
I would say definitely in a building
phase. You know, I'm sure lots of people
are. I'm sure everyone's installing
Clawbot or Open Claw or whatever it's
called these days and getting their
stuff built. But um, which I haven't I
haven't messed with it much. I'm still
using Cloud Code for everything. But um,
but yeah, I've been using Cloud Code to
build a ton of stuff on the side.
Inadvertently, it has found like two
bugs, but uh I think that it will
hopefully pay dividends over over the
course of the year. You were just
telling me that uh you're building some
like program specific automation, huh?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think I started off the
year and I looked at all my notes.
Obviously, you know, I take excessive
notes of everything I do. And I just
realized there's a couple of big
inefficiencies and some really nice
quality of life things that I just
needed to bite the bullet and start
building. Um, and now obviously with
Claude
and actually knowing how to vibe code
properly, it just makes life so much
easier. So, I I set myself some time out
in the calendar and committed to it. And
it's going pretty well so far with the
stuff that I did want to make. I'm just
excited to unleash it when it's finally
ready in a couple of weeks.
>> Yeah. I was going to ask you, is it more
passive stuff like you know automation
like you know monitoring and that sort
of thing or is this stuff that you plan
to use like when you're actively
hacking?
>> Both. So my idea is in my notes, it
makes a lot of sense to me mentally in
my notes, but it's called like the
hacker's toolkit, and there's four
different areas of my hunting
methodology, if you want to call it
that, that could be improved by some
tooling, some improvements to existing
tooling I have, and just better tracking
and monitoring of a lot of the things
that I use when I'm hunting on some
targets. So, it's basically
consolidating all my pain points and
trying to like hit him out all in one by
creating this hackers toolkit which will
uh hopefully pay dividends, but we'll
see. It's early days. It might not work,
but hopefully in a future episode I'll
have some good some good news.
>> Yeah, I do feel like that's the thing is
a lot of times I'll get something set up
and be like, "Oh, this is going to be
awesome." And then I check on it three
days later and it's like it crashed or
it was like looping on an error, you
know, or something like that. Um because
when you're not writing the code by
hand, it's like you don't know exactly
where to be checking where it could
break. You know, obviously you can tell
tell Clyde to like write test and check
check it all. But
>> exactly.
>> I think you and I have a bunch of
stories for the day. Uh but one thing we
did want to mention up front,
>> you know, Justin had an awesome Google
episode uh last week was that they I
think they might have meant to mention
it on the pod and so this is us
mentioning it now. Basically, Google
Cloud VRP has a swag bonus for critical
thinking listeners. All you got to do is
mention in your report the podcast um
and it can be like a cash or a credit
reward or any report that gets rewarded
and they will uh like send out some
bonus swag for critical thinker
listeners. So,
>> that's pretty that's pretty awesome. I
don't think I've ever seen that happen
before. And
>> I'm going I'm going to do it right now.
I forgot to do that on one of my
reports.
>> So, I haven't looked at Google. We're
just talking about this off air. And I
do want to look at Google this year. So,
I think this has expedited it to try and
get a bug in before April just so I can
have some swag. What is the Google swag
like actually? You have quite a lot of
it.
>> Oh man. I So, some of it's incredible.
Um, yeah. I'll kind of do like a super
quick rundown. They have like pretty
nice shirts that I really like. It just
says Google buck hunters in black on the
front and then it has like some sort of
design on the back depending on the
event. And then my favorite piece of
swag is they they have like thick
sweatshirts that are really nice like
thick black hoodies. And um there was
like a really small AI life hacking
event, you know, like two or three years
ago um that didn't have like an official
MVH, but they like gave me MVH and so
that's like my favorite hoodie. It has
like some AI art on the back. But in
general, their MVH's are always those
like sick dragonflies, too. So they they
I mean they have some good stuff. They
they gave out some pillows. um recently.
So that was fun. But
>> yeah, damn. I need to get my hands on
some of it. My entire wardrobe is like a
little bit of Bug Crowd, mostly Hacker
One, and then like the rest is 80%
Amazon, which isn't
>> I'm wearing one. I don't wear much, but
I think it's like a really fun one.
>> What program is that from?
>> Uh it's just a bug crowd shirt.
>> Oh, nice. Nice. Sorry, I couldn't quite.
>> Yes, it's all your bugs are belong to
us. I I personally love that meme and
that joke. Every time I wear this shirt,
my wife makes fun of it, but
>> it don't matter. It does not matter. But
right, in terms of getting started on
some research, do you want to start?
You've got some pretty cool things that
I haven't seen on this list.
>> Yeah, sure. So, we have a ton of like
interesting research from the last
month. Um, we've had some episodes where
we didn't get to cover as much. Um, the
one I'm the most jealous that I didn't
find, so I'll mention it first because
it's super cool, was uh this Cloudflare
one. And so I'm going to open it up and
share my screen real quick.
>> Mhm.
>> For the listeners, uh there was a cloud
flare. Um you know, they're calling it a
zero day here. I guess it it's probably
valid as a zero day found by Fears Off.
Um and
basically
they there was like um what would you
call this? there was like a a
misconfiguration that completely
disabled their W if the request was made
towelnown
acme challenge. Um and so if the token
in the request match any active
challenge across their entire
infrastructure, not just the target
domain, then it would pass through
completely unfiltered to the origin
server. So my attacker could like craft
request through that to bypass all of
the customer configured W rules. Um, and
uh, yeah, let's scroll down here and let
me show you.
Wow. Yeah, whenever they first found
this, it was totally absurd. So yeah,
there was this actuator ENV endpoint for
well actually I don't know if this was
custom or if this was for every user but
basically for anyone that relied on
Cloudflare W for blocking stuff you
could go straight to the actuator like
ENV. So what I'm showing for the
listeners is basically a screenshot
where they showed that you know it's you
know the testing domain
acme challenge slash then the actual
challenge token which could be true for
anybody. So you can do it with your own
token, right, to attack other victims
and then the then a path traversal up to
whatever path you were trying to get to,
right? So in this case it was like dot
dot colon dot dot or do semicolon dot
semicolon dot semicolon and then
actuator v env. And so then they dumped
the actuator env.
>> Wow. So to summarize, you could have
your own cloudflare instance. You could
generate one of these tokens on what's
the endpoint? well-known Acme challenge
and then token
>> you include that token was it
you include that token in the well-known
path
>> on the target domain and then you just
path traverse to whatever path you
wanted to bypass the W
>> yeah like you're able to see on my
screen I think right in this screenshot
you know they're using fearsoft.org But
like let's say that your the victim was
google.com, right? Or whatever. Then you
would spin up this get your your token,
but then you would put the in the path
for the victims.
>> Yeah.
>> Nice. Wow. That and they have Cloudflare
have a bug bounty program, don't they?
Or do they not?
>> I believe they do. I didn't see at the
bottom. Did they get a bounty? Submitted
hacker one. Yeah.
>> Nice. Very nice. And the crypto.com
security team.
>> Oh, very nice. uh yeah, who they
approached to independently verify it. I
wonder I wonder if they were hoping for
a big crypto bounty from that. So like
let's submit this to the company that
will be impacted the most here and then
uh and then work backwards from there.
Honestly, I mean, it's a little um it's
probably not it's a little more green
hat than uh white hat, but I do think
sometimes when there are these like
widespread issues like this that can
affect multiple companies in really
significant ways, this the bounty you
would get by submitting it to the vendor
only sometimes doesn't feel worthy of
the payout, you know, and I think that
in some cases like this, it would be
nice if some of the the victims would
also, especially if they're bigger
companies with big budgets, kind of
contribute to the bounty in some way.
For sure. I think that's been a topic of
discussion for some of the recon guys as
well, right? When they are finding these
sort of like configurationes bugs which
can be patched at the vendor side, but
it actually impacts a lot of other
things. Where do you report it? Do you
put the green hat on? Do you put the Do
you put the uh ethical hat on? But very
nice bug. And when did this get patched?
Was this this month or
>> I think it was January 14th. Yeah. Uh
no, actually, sorry. No, back in
October. I only saw this in January,
though. I wonder when it when this blog
post went live.
>> So, it says it went live or last update
it was January 19th, 2026.
>> Yeah, I was thinking it was pretty new,
so they must have just waited to get
their stuff together before they
disclosed.
>> Damn. Yeah, that's very nice. Very
impactful as well.
>> That's the stuff I love looking for.
Like, I love serverside stuff like that
to expose secrets and hidden paths.
>> Yeah, very nice. Let me share my screen.
I've got one
uh
where are we? Which matches quite nicely
with the kind of bugs I like to
look for. Let me know if you can see my
screen.
>> Yes, sir. I can see it.
>> So, this one made me laugh because you
know when you're getting spammed from
whatever
email chain you subscribed to like two
years ago and you're like, "That would
be useful." And then you just get
hammered every day ever since with
>> check out this product blah blah blah.
Well,
>> this works with bug bounty. All of our
listeners know that pain so deeply like,
oh man, just getting pinged. And when
they don't have a good unsubscribe, it's
like you can never get away from it.
>> Yeah. And I'm personally I've hit over
50,000 unread emails. So like this one
put a smile to my face. So this research
on the by Lorett Haltman I think it's
pronounced. Sorry if I just completely
butchered that. turns the list
unsubscribe into an SSRF and XSS gadget.
Now the way it works is there's a SMTP
header called list unsubscribe which is
now standardized um that is supported by
however many mail servers it's it's
standardized. It's a thing now the it
allows clients to provide an easy
standardized way to unsubscribe from a
mail list that you're getting absolutely
hammered by. Do you think that's how the
Google button works in Gmail? You know,
that like unsubscribe button that
automatically appears when you kind of
hover over emails.
>> I have wondered. I might have to look
after this call actually because I'm
intrigued. Um, but the field essentially
looks like this for the people that are
listening. It's list- unsubscribe, and
then open bracket mail to list host at
whatever subject. And then you can
provide
URLs and mail to schemas there. Now that
looks pretty standard, but what's
interesting here is that the RFC states
that you can include HTTP URIs and a
mail 2 link. So this researcher
basically thought, okay, what happens if
we had an arbitrary HTTPS scheme here or
maybe other schemes? Now they went on to
get some pretty impactful bugs on a lot
of u mail servers. So one CV they got
issued off the back of this CV 2025
is a stored XSS affecting hoorde mail.
Now, essentially what happens is when
you include a URI, and this doesn't have
to be a HTTPS or mail to URI, it can be
a JavaScript URI. It renders in a
backend portal. So, they include a
JavaScript URI within their unsubscribe
and they've got proof of concept scripts
on here as well for the listeners if you
did want to come and have a look at
this. And you can see here in the list
unsubscribe, it's a simple JavaScript
URI confirm document. aign sent that
through and this actually pops on the
back end of Horde mail which is pretty
nice. So it's kind of a blind excss if
I'm following this one correct. So that
was one of them. Now next up they also
found an SSRF in nextcloud
and exactly
the same methodology.
When the user clicks unsubscribe from a
mailing list um it issues a serverside
request. Now during their research it
looked like NexCloud were allowing
requests to arbitrary internal
destinations as well. But building this
research out a little bit more they
later discovered that this is only
possible to hit internal hosts in
nextcloud if this allow local remote
servers is set to true in their
configuration. So the radius is a little
bit smaller there. But they've also
included a proof of concept Python
script if you did want to try this on
any deployments that you find. And it's
literally just list unsubscribe with the
target UR URL in there as well. Um,
pretty nice, really nice research
because for me, this is one of those
pieces that
is
an unlooked upon attack surface where
everyone sort of knows that this exists,
but actually using it as a primitive for
blind XSS and SSRF, probably a little
bit less known. And they've got some
really nice CVE from this as well. So, I
can only assume that this is going to be
in a few other frameworks out there.
Definitely one to test for, I think.
>> Yeah, 1 million%. And I think um it does
feel like, you know, the LA in the last
year or two, there have been so many
bugs from stuff that like whenever we're
as bug hunters like hunting, we just
kind of ignore it. Like some of those
like trace headers and like all you
know, just like little things that are
here and there. Like you always see
unsubscribe and you kind of look for
CSRF to unsubscribe others and then no
one really submits it because it would
be like a super low or something. But uh
but you you know you're always looking
for like just like little
vulnerabilities like this and you know
we've all seen unsubscribe links.
They're always like kind of interesting
because they often don't need off. You
know you can just you can just like get
to them and then put in anybody's email
and it'll unsubscribe them or whatever.
But that's usuallyformational or you
know like a $100 low or something. U
this is a really cool way to to find a
high impact bug on that same on the same
[snorts] skill.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So takeaways, if you find a
mail server and it supports the list
unsubscribe functionality, try and embed
any sort of SSRF targets you want to
embed in there. And also try blind XSS
payloads as well because they could
trigger. So nice research.
Sweet. I'll go next. This is
uh Heroku Postgress vulnerability by
Alistair. Um
this was kind of interesting. I think
this might have been found at a live
hacking event that you and I were in.
But um
>> Oh yeah, of course. Okay.
>> Yeah. But uh anyways, this was is like a
really cool bug. And um you should just
read the whole the read the whole post.
But the TLDDR here is that if you can
overwrite functions which are
automatically called by super users then
you can basically control what that
super user is doing. This is like um my
buddy um I I'll shout him out here. His
name's Mike Branado. he um got like uh
third best bug or second best bug for
Google or second best writeup or
something like a couple years ago for
Google when they used to do those big
payout bonuses for like best write up of
the year. And he um looked for this
similar vulnerability across many
different cloud providers because they
often will be in the background running
metrics, right? Like let's say you're
Google or AWS and you've got a bunch of
managed servers, you probably need to
keep metrics and health data on that,
right? Like how many rows, like what's
the size of the DB, you know, like I
don't know, basically you just want
usage statistics because you want to
know how many databases are out there,
how big they are, how much they're
costing you, all these things, right?
Well, whenever so they they kind of have
to have like a god token of sorts,
right? They have to have like a super
super user who logs in to these DBs,
pulls metrics on them, and then logs
out. And um so there's often a potential
vulnerability there where if you can
overwrite the function that is being
called by that super user then whatever
then you know with whatever malicious
action you want to get taken. So let's
say let's say there's like a super super
user and a super user and if you want to
escalate up to being super super user
you need to change that function to be a
function which sets your permissions to
be higher right or if you want to read
other users databases like cross-tenant
vulnerabilities in cloud providers which
is obviously one of the highest impacts
you can have um you know then you would
change that function to let's say like
read a different database for a
different user based on you know kind of
like an idor of sorts but really it's
just this super super user has access to
every Postgress and um so anyways um you
should just read Alistair's post but
that's basically uh what they did right
they they overrode a function um and
then when it was executed by the RDS
super user it gave them those that
permission so um
>> very nice I can see as well there's a
note here that it was it won
extraordinary research contribution
award from Salesforce as well and this
is one of those attack surfaces where
like I'm intrigued by it because as you
say it's a managed service and obviously
you and thousands of other tenants are
running there but without this kind of
research I wouldn't even know where to
begin to start dissecting some attack
surface like this
>> and the other things as well it's always
going to be incredibly impactful and I
can only imagine if you spend a long
time on a single target having this
fundamental understanding of the service
would be really really beneficial
because this is like a fundamental core
service that's going to be embedded
throughout the entire target. So, this
is a really nice write up and it
actually covers quite in depth a lot of
the architectural decisions as well that
they've made around the Heroku
infrastructure and how the customer
databases are configured as well. So,
yeah, this is really nice. I'm going to
bookmark that.
>> Nice, dude. You're up.
>> Right. What have we got next?
>> You want to feature the CTB research?
Yeah, let's get the CTB researcher up.
So, for the listeners, we have some
fresh CTB research up on the lab and the
clients are guys and well, just about
every bug hunter is going to like this,
but this is by uh it's really a bad name
for
>> Thank you. [gasps]
on paraser discrepancies and parasa
discrepancies has been quite a hot topic
on the pod on previous things and the
core concept here with para
discrepancies is that we can cause a
confusion between two different paths is
that pass the exact same input string
but they produce different results. Now,
this one was really nice because the
impact here allowed them to get excss on
Chrome and Firefox by abusing and hold
on, let me just get this right. List
based and singleton fields which are
described in the RFC as different ways
header fields can be defined. Now, when
I started reading this, this is going to
be one of those things that you
intuitively know because when you see
accept headers, you see this format all
the time when you've got except
text/html,
application/x html, so on and so forth.
Now,
only certain headers and fields
accept this format. Not every header and
field can accept that. And what defines
that is a different rule in a different
RFC called the ABNF rule. And that
defines what header syntax can be used.
Now
throughout this research, it actually
built upon and let me get this name
right as well. The original research by
Black Fan um when they done the um mime
type validation research, we covered it
previously on an earlier episode. We'll
get that reference in the hacker notes.
Um and essentially it allowed
a application/JSON
um semicolon,
text/HTML
to be passed as application/JSON
by a backend library but by the browser
get passed as text/HTML allow XSS. Now,
he does a massive deep dive into exactly
how these concept type headers are
passed and even gives code snippets from
the Chromium codebase here about their
behavior and why they handle different
things. I'm not going to go into it
completely. Um, but it's quite an
in-depth write up. Very good. Now, the
other thing as well is that the last
match wins problem. Now, how does
Chromium handle and pass a content type
response headers value? It goes into
that because that affects the
exploitability a little bit. Again,
loads and loads of code snippets here.
Um, very, very long read, so I'm not
going to dive into all that.
>> But the part that I did want to mention
is right at the bottom,
uh, where are we? is a summary table
which is really nice and I think the
community and maybe even us should build
on and it gives a summary of different
libraries compared to browsers and how
they pass the singleton and other fields
and how they actually validate them. Um
there's been previous research I think
around the cache deception if you
remember what dropped last year at
Defcon and it gave the really nice
fields of different frameworks different
web browsers um different frameworks
CDN's and how they validate different
types and this is exactly that very nice
to read very nice to check if you've got
[snorts] one of these libraries that
you're encountering as well but there's
going to be a ton more libraries out
there which have this exact same problem
so I recommend that this is probably
going to be a ripe area to hunt on if
you have the time and willpower to do
it.
>> Yeah, man. I feel like some of the
coolest things are whenever there's like
some new way to, you know, get HTML to
be processed client side. Uh whenever
you can like all of a sudden reunlock or
or basically do a first unlock for a
new, you know, path to XSS is like the
one of the coolest like types of
research that can be done.
Yeah, it's a really good write up. I
didn't do it justice because there's a
lot of code snippets here which will
give you really solid fundamentals on
how mine types are handled and why these
little RFC quirks are producing this
behavior. Um, but you can't really speak
all all of this out on a podcast. So, I
recommend everyone to go and give this
one a read. It's really nice. Um, we'll
probably land you a few bugs in the
right context on a couple of targets.
>> Sweet. I have a fun little thing to talk
about. I think you'll like this from
some of your AI testing. Did you see the
magic string? That's like the iCar
string.
>> I saw some chatter on Twitter, but what
what what is this research you speak?
>> Yeah, I'll show you once my page
actually loads. I can share it.
Okay. Come on. Wow. Did this load for
you? I'm going to message it to you. Oh,
actually, I closed Discord.
It's hackingthe.cloud
doesn't load right now. Um,
I can explain it without it, but it's
kind of annoying. All right. Yeah. So,
I'll go ahead and start describing it
while this thing starts to load.
Basically, um, any of our listeners who
have not worked in blue team might not
know what the IICAR string is. ICAR is E
I C A R. The IICAR string is like a um
virus detection string that is benign
but which every AV would flag as
malicious. So it's a way that you can
basically test your antivirus solution
and um you know a lot of people who are
like building
um socks or NOX like secure operation
centers or network operation centers who
will often have like alerting pipelines
and detection pipelines they'll use
IICAR strings to basically test that.
So, you know, [snorts] they'll have like
a a file on disk for one of their
employees or their email or or they will
email one of their employees a file like
an IICAR file or an ICAR string and the
goal is that the detection will pick it
up, right? Reject the email or send an
alert to the team and um I I've actually
often thought it would be kind of cool
to have one of those for AI models and
um but anyways, it actually does exist.
So, I'll share the screen now. It's
actually loading. Um here we go. I don't
know if the website was down or if it
was my internet, but basically Claude's
magic string denial of service. So,
Anthropics uh documents a magic string
that intentionally triggers a refusal, a
stop reason refusal um when streaming
classifiers intervene. So, basically,
you know, the guardrails that they
implement will automatically drop a
refusal if this magic string is in the
response, right? And it's right here.
>> Um
>> Oh, wow. and and I think this opens the
door for so many cool attacks and so
much neat research because one I think
if you don't want your website parsed
just put this on the you just put this
on the source right and so it'll still
be parsed by any parsers that are being
written by Gemini or that are being
written by Chad GBT or whatever and of
course scrapers could go you know
offuscate this like you know gp it out
before it goes to the LLM but in general
it's like pretty neat right that you
could put it there as a way to do that.
Secondly, I think that um if you have
some way to impact the context via like
indirect prompt injection, if you can
get this in the indirect prompt
injection, then the model will just stop
responding. So if you could get it to if
you could get this to come back for
every user's query, then all of a sudden
it would basically deny of service their
entire usage of the app. And the
[snorts] reason why that's kind of nice
is most companies are building on like a
single provider. Anthropic is pretty
common for that because they often have
the best models and so um you know
that's like a great way to do that. I
wonder if you could also selectively
doss people if you said if you had like
an MCP server um where the majority of
people are using cloud code or cloud end
cursor or whatever or open claw you know
if this model string or if this string
came back from your MCP server um
dynamically for only users that you
wanted to doss or for like um like when
a user was taking a specific action that
you didn't want them to take or whatever
you know like I think it's really neat
that you can basically if there is a
user or like a company or whatever that
has an MCP server or some other REST API
that could then dynamically return this
string. It would would it would like
stop execution at that specific moment
in runtime, right? And it would be
interesting to then maybe use it to like
target your enemies or whatever, prevent
other nation state actors from using
this or whatever.
>> Yeah. And very context dependent, right?
Like we found our own version of this in
an assessment we done together where if
you could stop a process or a job
happening in the context that we found
it, it completely broke integrity for
the entire platform because it
fundamentally stopped working. I would
like to see
all model providers have something like
this just to be able to have that
coverage for when you are encountering
something other than Claude. This is a
really nice
thing to have in your back pocket. Did
they say exactly why that they've come
out and produced this?
>> Uh let's go look. I actually haven't
read Anthropics documentation on it
here. Share this tab instead. [snorts]
>> If you need to test refusal handling in
your application, you can use the
special test string as your prompt.
>> It's Yeah, it's just for ease of testing
because you know I mean you know as well
as I do that whenever you're testing
LMS, they're just so non-deterministic
that it can be like pretty flaky. So, if
I think that if you're wanting to see
like let's say you wrote a front-end
application and you want to see how it
handles a refusal to make sure it fails
gracefully and doesn't like pop up a big
red 500 error in your app or something,
then I think this is kind of what that's
for. It's like let's make sure we have
graceful handling of rejections. Like a
lot of companies would have some sort of
like automatic text that comes back that
says,
>> you know, sorry, your message triggered
our guardrails. Please try again with
like a retry button, right? So I think
it's like for like testing UI or UX
elements like that.
>> Yeah. Nice. I can see as well in the
threat model that it mentions anthropic
state. A single injection can become
sticky. If the poisons turn remains in
history, all future turns will keep
refusing until the application drops or
rewrites the offending content. So yeah,
it could be very impactful in the right
context.
>> Yeah, [snorts] cuz I mean if you think
way think about the way these models
work, you know, it's just one big input
blob. Technically, we kind of chunk it
up as like previous messages, you know,
user assistant, whatever, like, you
know, multi-turn. But it's at the end of
the day, it's all just one string to go
straight into the model uh at at
execution time, at inference time. And
so if that string is in there anywhere,
it makes me want to do things like uh
name my user that string, you know,
name, you know, put my email like as
like a plus alias, like reszo plus that
big long string at wehacker1.com. like
just basically just get that string
anywhere I can. Uh and just like see if
it breaks stuff. Kind of
>> uh itarkens back to the old school uh
hacker mentality of just breaking stuff
for fun, you know.
>> I'm not going to lie, I was hoping the
string would be a bit shorter, so it
could get through a lot of validation
because obviously you're restricted by
characters, but it is quite a long
string. I wonder if it would require the
full string in order to fully think it's
a stop or if you could do partials. I
think it has to be the full one, but I
don't sure.
>> Yeah. Um, it would be fun to register
that as a subdomain. Obviously, you
can't underscore, so it's not going to
work. But I wonder if it's that second
part. Like, I wonder if it's anthropic
magic string trigger refusal or if it's
just that second number and letter
thing.
>> I'm going to have to give that a go at
some point this week, I think.
>> Yeah.
>> But very nice. Um, I will go next. Now,
this one is kind of a long write up, but
I really liked it as I've been doing
some mobile testing lately and the chain
is pretty crazy. So, by this one's by Do
you want to say that name? Reso le
>> lies Muhammad.
>> Yeah, we'll go with that.
>> I think I think it's just lies. I don't
know.
>> And the attack chain is actually pretty
crazy. It results in remote code
execution in an Android application. And
at a high level, the chain is a deep
link trust bypass to access a web view
JavaScript interface abusing that
interface to perform an arbitrary file
right through a path reversal. Abusing
that to
uh hijack an overthe-air
update, writing a malicious code bundle
which then gets loaded on restart to
full rce.
>> Actually, I actually I figured that out
last week as well. I just didn't want to
report it. [laughter]
>> This is like one of those mega chains
that you look at and you think fair play
to whoever found this because it
obviously took a bit of time to craft.
Um,
>> so the initial entry point, if you've
done any mobile testing, you're probably
pretty used to looking for any sort of
deep link schemes that handle uh URLs
and they're often only accepted from
trusted domains. Now the flaw in this
although it was looking good was that
the app blindly trusted all subdomains
of google.com and we'll touch upon that
later [snorts] and the web view um the
app had an internal browser [sighs]
which had a JavaScript native message
handler which used post message which
was initially accessible from any host
or domain but it turned out that it was
only Google that's touched upon later on
in the research. Now the bridge the
interface
um exposed the native message handler
but it required a registration handshake
process before it was actually
recognized as like uh a native handler
that it could actually talk to. So in
the right up here you can see that it
was a post message
um containing data with an action in it
with your receiver name, your sender,
all that stuff. and then it had to be
initialized by a secondary post message
after that. And once you done that, you
had access to all of the native actions.
Now, with mobile testing, when you're in
the context of a web view, if you do see
any um functions decorated by the uh
JavaScript interface, that means that
they are accessible through that web
view. And what that means is you can
access it through like window dot um in
this case native message handler dot um
name. So it could be like window.native
message handler function name and you
can access it through that web view. So,
it's kind of always like it should get
your hacker senses tingling if you see
at any point because they're exposing
native Java calls through that web view
[snorts] which is always something to to
look out for. Then the application
implemented some form of file sharing
which was where the path reversal came
into play and it was simply grabbing the
file name from one of the post messages
doing some checks which didn't actually
do much um concatenating the file name
onto the uh cache directory path and
[snorts] then simply allowing a file
right to that path without actually
validating it. So I think the
misconception there was that the post
message is only ever going to come from
a trusted origin. So they didn't
actually need to worry about it. But
that's wrong. Now one thing I didn't
realize which is quite nice is there's
React Native overthe-air updates for
mobile apps and it allows mobile apps to
update their JavaScript bundles without
having to redeploy to the app store and
getting all that process in place. Now,
it makes sense to have that because
obviously developers wouldn't want to go
through that entire process again, but I
just didn't ever think about it as a tax
surface, which is why I really like this
blog. So, they started looking at how
the update mechanism worked. And to cut
a long story short, they realized that
they can actually use the path reversal
to overwrite uh some of the files that
the overtheair update look um overtheair
update uses. So they get through this,
they start building out this chain.
Fantastic. But there's one step towards
the end is that in order to verify the
deep link, there's actually a server
side check that
sends to the to an API endpoint to check
and verify whether or not it's trusted
or not. So, it take the take the URI
from what you're sending, send it
externally, say trusted, yes, no, um,
and then deny or permit based on that
action. Now, you'd usually think game
over here, but after some good recon or
fuzzing, whatever they've done, um, they
figured out that it trusts google.com,
but it also trusts google.com and all of
its subdomains.
So using that, and this is a gadget I
didn't know existed in Google, is that
you can use sites.google.com
to host arbitrary pages through an
iframe. So once that's there, what
they've done is they have their web page
in an iframe and register a post message
listener to deliver and talk through
that embedded iframe because you're
framing it from sites.google.com,
which is pretty nice. I didn't know that
existed. So
with that out the way,
they rewrite the OTAA press.xml
and plant their malicious React Native
bundle at that path and then the next
time the app restarts the overtheair
loader, reads the compromised config
file, finds a pending update, and it
actually loads the attackers bundle.
Now, when that happens, it's essentially
full rce in the application context. And
they even done some really nice things
in their exploit as well, like they
added um checks for version detection to
ensure that their exploit was cross
version compatible. So, regardless of
what version that their victim's app was
running on, they'd always say that there
was an update required. So, it always
overwrote the OTAA update regardless of
what version they're running and then
deploys the malicious bundle as you can
see in the post. So, really nice. As
soon as the user quits out of the app,
triggers a restart and that's when RC
gets triggered. And they've done some
pretty nasty stuff here. They loaded all
their OR tokens from the keychain
manager. um disclosed a couple of
sensitive files from the database
um directory, some stuff from the files
directory and exfiltrated it all
externally to their attacker controlled
site and kind of a crazy exploit chain.
They included a really nice diagram as
well of how the entire exploit works um
which will help listeners revisit and
get a better comprehension of it. But
crazy attack chain, man. and uh RC in a
mobile app's pretty cool.
>> Yeah, dude. Absolutely wild. And
>> I was going to tell you, I I feel like
um it's not uncommon to see star. Google
in CSPs, so that sites. Google is a
great tip. Um yeah.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Funnily enough, when I
was walking through this, I actually
played around with this to check if it
was actually [snorts] legit, and it of
course it was, but I was trying to embed
one of my blind XSS hosts, and it
wouldn't embed. And I was thinking, why
is it not embedded? I accidentally set
an X-frame options header on my web
server configuration, which meant I've
accidentally broke some of my XSS
payloads without realizing. And by going
through this blog, I actually figured
out that that shouldn't be there. Remove
the header and it works. So I'd dread to
think how many blind XSS I've missed
because I've had a funky X frame option.
>> Oh, at some point you set that and so it
like yeah, it made it not work
>> by complete accident. But we'll see.
Let's see if we get any more triggers.
>> One thing is really cool here that I
noticed, I'm sure you saw at the end of
the blog was Genie is actually a
product. So they have an AI based um
basically product that is almost like
shift agents or you know um like some of
the you know current AI hacking tools
but it's for specifically hacking mobile
apps and so if there are any researchers
out there who you know are looking for
you know wanting to get into mobile
researching or mobile um hacking for bug
bounty and want to have like a little
mobile hacking AI assistant maybe try
out Genie AI. Yeah, it's
>> not sponsored, but
>> No, no, no, not at all. It's on my to-do
list. They've actually got some pretty
cool research as well off the back of
this, and this is incredibly impactful.
So, I'll be checking it out. And it's
Genie AI.
>> Uh, I had a cool post from Zero, but I
might wait and let um Justin explain it
or explain it next week because I
actually have to drop. [snorts] Um, and
I think you had one more. Maybe we'll
save that one for next week as well.
>> Yeah, sure. Um
yeah, there's no problem. I'm just
trying to think which one it was. Yeah,
it's a bit of a primer. In fact, I'll
just really quickly say it now. Um it is
a very and this is one for people which
aren't as client side inclined as well
both of us I guess compared to Justin
anyway. Um and it's really a quick
primer on DOMXS.
It covers some of the uh trusted types
API as well which is coming out um if
people aren't familiar with it. It's
being implemented more in some targets
and it's a way to harden browsers
against DOM XSS and it breaks down a
couple of DOM based polygots as well and
I just thought it's quite a nice read
for some people newer to the client side
world um if you did want a quick primer
and it's not an overly long article. I
just thought it'd be appreciated by some
of the community. So that is on
blog.jsmon.sh
and it's domx is not dead the rise of
polygot payloads. So that's a good
little read.
Sweet. Um
okay. Yeah, I think that's good. I um
I know that we've got to do a little
another recording slash ad read here in
a second, but besides that, I think
we're good. Man, you got anything else
you wanted to mention before we sign
off?
No, other than remember to include
critical thinking somewhere in your
Google reports until the end of April to
receive bonus swag. Remember to do that
free swag.
>> Sweet. Yep. I went and did it uh when we
first started recording. [laughter]
>> Cool. Very nice.
>> See you guys. Peace.
>> Peace.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content,
>> [music]
>> uh or if you want to support the show,
head over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, [music] hackalongs,
exclusive content, and a full-time
hunters guild if you're a full-time
hunter. [music] It's a great time, trust
me. All right, I'll see you there.